Guide to the Stanford University, Office of Residential Education, Crothers Global Citizenship program posters SC1117
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Office of Residential Education, Crothers Global Citizenship Program posters
2010-2016
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Office of Residential Education. Crothers Global Citizenship Program
SC1117
3 Linear Feet (66 items)
The collection consists of promotional posters for Crothers Global Citizenship Program guest speaker events. Speakers include Kofi Annan, Gerhard Casper, John Prendergast, Kenneth Arrow, Carlos Pascual, Richard Goldstone, and George Clooney. Many posters are signed by guest speakers.
Biographical / Historical
The Crothers Global Citizenship Program is a theme dorm based in Crothers Hall, an undergraduate residence at Stanford University. Founded in 2010, the program gives students with an interest in global issues the opportunity to interact with resident fellows, Stanford scholars, and distinguished visitors. It is affiliated with the Freman-Spogli Institute for International Studies.
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use.
Acquisition Information
Materials were received via administrative transfer in 2012-2016.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of promotional posters for Crothers Global Citizenship Program guest speaker events. Speakers include Kofi Annan, Gerhard Casper, John Prendergast, Kenneth Arrow, Carlos Pascual, Richard Goldstone, and George Clooney. Many posters are signed by guest speakers.
Globalization.; World citizenship; Stanford University. Office of Residential Education. Crothers Global Citizenship Program; Stanford University. Office of Residential Education. Crothers Global Citizenship Program
- Posters, 2012
  - "'Is Global Citizenship an Oxymoron?': A Conversation with Gerhard Casper.", 2012 Oct 25 (Box 1)
  - "John Prendergast @ Crothers.", 2010 Nov 1-12 (Box 1)
  - "The S.T. Lee Distinguished Lecture: The Good News from Africa: Success Stories and Their Implications." With John Predergast. [2 copies], 2010 Nov 4 (Box 1)
  - "Crothers Global Citizenship Theme and STAND Present: George Clooney & John Prendergast: Sudan: Preventing the Next War." [2 copies], 2010 Nov 8 (Box 1)
  - "Crothers Global Citizenship Theme Dorm Presents: Global Citizenship, Activism, Social Networking, and Political Change." With John Prendergast and Jared Cohen. [2 copies], 2010 Nov 11 (Box 1)
  - "Scott Malcomson Speaks at Crothers." [2 copies], 2011 Jan 11 (Box 1)
  - "A Conversation with Richard Gowan." [2 copies], 2011 Feb 9 (Box 1)
  - "Change in the Middle East: A Conversation with Bruce Jones." [2 copies], 2011 Feb 15 (Box 1)
  - "A Conversation on Journalism in the Digital Age." With Beth Duff-Brown and Jigar Mehta. [2 copies], 2011 Feb 22 (Box 1)
  - "Camera as Witness Presents Garbage Dreams: Documentary Screening Followed by a Discussion with Stanford Students from Egypt and Q&A with Professor Jasmina Bojic." [2 copies], 2011 Mar 4 (Box 1)
  - "Crothers Global Citizenship Theme Presents General Joseph Ralston in Conversation about a Career Shaping U.S. Foreign Policy." [2 copies], 2011 Mar 29 (Box 1)
  - "Justice Goldstone Speaks at Crothers." With Richard Goldstone. [2 copies], 2011 Apr 25 (Box 1)
  - "Camera as Witness and Crothers Global Citizenship Present Bhutto." Discussion with Anush Ammar. Q&A with Jasmina Bojic. [2 copies], 2011 Apr 29 (Box 1)
  - "The Student Movement and the Struggle for Democracy in Venezuela: A Conversation with Roberto Patino.", 2011 Oct 19 (Box 1)
  - "Carlos Pascual: A Conversation with the U.S. Ambassador to Mexico.", 2011 Oct 21 (Box 1)
  - "A Crothers Global Citizenship Conversation with Kofi Annan." [2 copies], 2011 Nov 11 (Box 1)
  - "Camera as Witness and Crothers Global Citizenship Present In Whose Honor?" Introduction by Jasmina Bojic. Moderated by Carly Kohler., 2011 Nov 17 (Box 1)
  - "A Crothers Global Citizenship Conversation with Kavita Ramdas." [2 copies], 2011 Nov 29 (Box 1)
  - "A Crothers Global Citizenship Conversation with Senator Russell Feingold." [2 copies], 2012 Jan 17 (Box 1)
  - "A Crothers Global Citizenship Conversation with Sebastian Junger.", 2012 Jan 17 (Box 1)
  - "A Crothers Global Citizenship Conversation with Ren Ng.", 2012 Mar 7 (Box 1)
  - "A Crothers Global Citizenship Discussion: Harvard's Liberal-Arts Failure is Wall Street's Gain." With Felicty Barringer '72 and Philip Taubman '70., 2012 Apr 10 (Box 1)
  - "A Crothers Global Citizenship Conversation: HumBio, Morocco, and Consulting: A Long Road to International Development." With Lauren Peate '09., 2012 Apr 16 (Box 1)
  - "A Crothers Global Citizenship Conversation with Bill Guttentag.", 2012 Apr 17 (Box 1)
  - "A Crothers Global Citizenship Conversation with Kenneth Arrow.", 2012 Apr 23 (Box 1)
  - "Camera as Witness and Crothers Global Citizenship Present Burma Solider." Introduction by Jasmina Bojic. Discussion with Kate Morton '12., 2012 Apr 26 (Box 1)
  - "Crothers Global Citizenship Presents Medical School: The Road Not (Often) Taken: A Conversation with Paul Wise and Rajaie Batniji.", 2012 May 15 (Box 1)
  - "A Crothers Global Citizenship Conversation with Dani Rodrik." Moderated by Ishan Nath '12., 2012 May 24 (Box 1)
  - "A Crothers Global Citizenship Conversation with David Makovsky." Sponsored by thr Taube Center for Jewish Studies., 2012 Oct 23 (Box 1)
  - "A Crothers Global Citizenship Conversation with My Le.", 2012 Oct 24 (Box 1)
  - "A Crothers Global Citizenship Conversation on Obama and the Middle East with Bruce Jones.", 2012 Oct 30 (Box 1)
  - "A Crothers Global Citizenship Conversation with John Prendergast.", 2012 Nov 5 (Box 1)
  - "A Crothers Global Citizenship Conversation with Roberto Patiño.", 2012 Nov 13 (Box 1)
  - "A Crothers Global Citizenship Conversation with Stephen Krasner: Implications of the Election for American Foreign Policy.", 2012 Nov 14 (Box 1)
  - "A Crothers Global Citizenship Conversation with Steven Denning.", 2013 Jan 9 (Box 1)
  - "A Crothers Global Citizenship Conversation in Collaboration with the International Development Careers Group at Stanford with Peter Laugharn.", 2013 Jan 16 (Box 1)
  - "A Crothers Global Citizenship Conversation with Richard Powers.", 2013 Jan 23 (Box 1)
  - "A Crothers Global Citizenship Conversation with Pankaj Mishra.", 2013 Feb 25 (Box 1)
  - "The Robert G. Wesson Lecture: Pankaj Mishra.", 2013 Feb 28 (Box 1)
- Posters, 2015, Accession ARCH-2017-081
  - Jane Coyne, 2015 Nov 03 (Box 1)
  - Rachel Kleinfeld, 2016 Feb 22 (Box 1)
  - John Prendergast, 2016 (Box 1)
  - Rick Lowe, 2016 Feb 16 (Box 1)
  - Anders Fogh Rasmussen, 2015 Sep 24 (Box 1)
  - Siegfried Hecker, 2015 Sep 29 (Box 1)
  - Montek Isher Ahluwalia, 2015 Oct 14 (Box 1)
  - Andrew J. Bacevich, 2015 Oct 7 (Box 1)
  - Naomi Starkman, 2015 Oct 27 (Box 1)
  - Jane Coyne, 2015 Nov 03 (Box 1)
  - Chris Field Katherine Mach, 2015 Nov 10 (Box 1)
  - Dave Eggers, 2015 Nov 12 (Box 1)
  - Ertharin Cousin, 2015 Nov 20 (Box 1)
  - Katherin Toy, 2016 Jan 13 (Box 1)
  - Scotty McLennan, 2016 Jan 19 (Box 1)
  - Barney Frank, 2016 Feb 10 (Box 1)